<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Economics on Renato Vassallo</title>
    <link>https://renatovassallo.github.io/economics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Economics on Renato Vassallo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 12:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://renatovassallo.github.io/economics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Poverty and Inequality Assessment: The case of Malawi</title>
      <link>https://renatovassallo.github.io/economics/p1_malawi_poverty/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://renatovassallo.github.io/economics/p1_malawi_poverty/</guid>
      <description>Working with data from World Bank&amp;rsquo;s Integrated Households Surveys (IHS), we undertake an analysis of Malawi&amp;rsquo;s poverty and inequality indicators with the goal of aiding policymakers in the country design strategies to overcome the most critical challenges.
Main findings Poverty has remained intractable, despite some improvement. For example, since 2010 the percent of people living below the poverty line has fallen from 50% to 47%.
We show that the nature of poverty is different depending on the setting – though poverty is less prevalent in urban areas, there is significantly greater inequality than in rural areas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effects of External Shocks on Macroeconomic Fluctuations in Pacific Alliance Countries</title>
      <link>https://renatovassallo.github.io/economics/p2_external_shocks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://renatovassallo.github.io/economics/p2_external_shocks/</guid>
      <description>Given Pacific Alliance (PA) countries’ significant dependence on the external sector amidst volatile global financial conditions and increased trade openness, it is important to understand the time-varying impact of external shocks on these economies to assess their resilience. We use data for 1994-2019 to study the heterogeneity of responses to financial, real, and nominal external shocks in PA countries over time.
Highlights Despite higher dependence on the external sector, PA economies countries remain stable.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
